<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <document>
    <meta>
      <description>How to Ace a Voice‐Over Audition. Contrary to popular belief, you don't need to have a deep, low voice to have a successful voice-over career. The key is simply to identify the voice-over niche that is right for your voice. Get to know y...</description>
      <keywords>WikiHow, Ace a Voice&amp;acirc;Over Audition, wiki, how to articles, how to instructions, DIY, tips, howto, learn, how do I</keywords>
      <title>How to Ace a VoiceâOver Audition</title>
      <type>article</type>
      <url>http://www.wikihow.com/Ace-a-Voice%E2%80%90Over-Audition</url>
    </meta>
    <alter_lang/>
    <categories>
      <category>
        <c>Arts and Entertainment</c>
        <c>Performing Arts</c>
        <c>Acting</c>
        <c>Auditioning</c>
      </category>
    </categories>
    <general/>
    <methods>
      <method>
        <step>
          <em href="Do-a-Successful-Voice-Over.html" title="Do a Successful Voice Over">Get to know your voice</em>
          <details>
            <text>. Get a set of different scripts and record yourself reading each one. Then, play back what you've recorded and do a self-evaluation. Identify which type of script makes you feel most natural while recording in addition to which ones sound the best when played back.
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Play your recordings for friends and family.</em>
          <details>
            <text> Ask them to identify the most and least effective recordings. Use their feedback to help determine where you really excelled.
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Choose an appropriate voice-over field.</em>
          <details>
            <text> There is demand for even the most unique voices, so don't lose hope if you can't match the clear, deep voice on your voicemail machine. Use your unique qualities to your advantage! Voice-overs can be broken into the following three types:
</text>
            <ul>
              <li>
Straight Narration - Requires a very clear voice. Some scripts call for emotionally neutral narrators while others call for narrators that are emotionally involved. If you have an authoritative and clear voice, this is a good field for you.</li>
              <li>
Voice Acting - This field assigns your voice to a character. As a result, it requires unique voices with personality, accents, and attitude. As a voice actor, you may be asked to do the voice for a video game character or for an audio book.</li>
              <li>
Commercials - Calls for a narrator who can deliver the script in a very strict time limit. While it's important that the message be clear, the type of voice is less important than speed here.</li>
            </ul>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Practice reading out loud.</em>
          <details>
            <text> Overall the most important factor in being a great voice-over artist is being able to read aloud clearly, deliver the lines effectively, identify the main message of the script, and communicate that message naturally. Practice reading ahead while talking so that you do not stumble over your words come the big day.
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Study the script.</em>
          <details>
            <text> If you're lucky enough to receive the script beforehand, make sure you are extremely familiar with both the words and the message that the script is trying to convey. Find out which words work best with emphasis, and practice reading with different tones, speeds, and emotion. Once you find something that works best, practice it as much as you can in the days (or even weeks!) leading up to the audition.
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
      </method>
      <method>
        <step>
          <em>Study the script.</em>
          <details>
            <text> If you got the script beforehand, great. You should have already studied and practiced it. If you're seeing the script for the first time, take a couple minutes to read through it. Find the main message. With that message in mind, think about how you want to deliver the script. Practice reading out loud if you can.
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Don't cave under pressure.</em>
          <details>
            <text> Besides the high stress of auditioning for a job, a lot of companies will purposely heckle you to see how to respond under pressure. Stay cool, calm, and collected, and follow any directions you are given, even if you think you know better.
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
      </method>
    </methods>
    <tips>
      <tip>
        <ul>
          <li>Don't expect to become a millionaire off your first voice-over job. The first couple years of voice overs can be extremely challenging—don't expect to make more than $2500 in your first year. As you become more established, you'll be able to find higher-paying positions and may even be able to have a full time voice-over career.</li>
          <li>Prestige is key. Don't pass up a small job if it's for a big company. Even recording something like "Download is complete!" for a company like Yahoo! or AOL will be impressive to future employers.</li>
        </ul>
      </tip>
    </tips>
    <warnings/>
    <things/>
    <ingredients/>
    <related_pages/>
  </document>
</root>
