<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <document>
    <categories>
      <category>
        <c>Food and Entertaining</c>
        <c>Recipes</c>
        <c>Baking</c>
        <c>Cakes</c>
      </category>
    </categories>
    <method>
      <step>
        <em>Start by reading the ingredient list and directions before you begin.</em>
        <details>
          <text> It's important to have every ingredient you need ready to go. You don't want to be running to the grocery store during preparation. The final product can flop if a key ingredient is left out.</text>
        </details>
      </step>
      <step>
        <em>Prepare your cake pans.</em>
        <details>
          <text> Be sure to have the correct size or shape of the pan. </text>
          <a href="/Make-a-Strawberry-Bundt-Cake" title="Make a Strawberry Bundt Cake">Bundt cakes</a>
          <text> require bundt pans, while others can be baked in a variety of sizes. Grease pans to avoid sticking. Use about a half of tablespoon of </text>
          <a href="/Make-Butter-by-Whipping" title="Make Butter by Whipping">butter</a>
          <text> or vegetable shortening on a paper towel and rub the inside of the pan. Sprinkle about a tablespoon or two of </text>
          <a href="/Make-Flour" title="Make Flour">flour</a>
          <text> on top. Flour the pans on the sides to help the cake adhere to the sides as it bakes. This will ensure that the top is flatter, which is important for layered cakes. Shake and dump out any excess flour and set the pans to the side.
</text>
        </details>
      </step>
      <step>
        <em>Preheat the oven</em>
        <details/>
      </step>
      <step>
        <em>Measure ingredients</em>
        <details/>
      </step>
      <step>
        <em>Mix the cake batter as specified on the recipe.</em>
        <details>
          <text> Some recipes can be mixed with a stand or </text>
          <a href="/Remove-Stuck-Beaters-on-a-Mixer" title="Remove Stuck Beaters on a Mixer">hand mixer</a>
          <text>. Be cautious as steps can instruct to fold in flour or other ingredients with a rubber spatula. While mixing, stop occasionally to scrape down the sides of the bowl with a spatula or spoon to ensure that everything is mixed thoroughly.
</text>
        </details>
      </step>
      <step>
        <em>Pour the batter evenly into the prepared pans.</em>
        <details>
          <text> Fill the pans 2/3 of the way full, as the cake will rise during baking. Gently tap the cake pan on the counter top to release any large air bubbles in the batter.
</text>
        </details>
      </step>
      <step>
        <em>Place the pans on the center rack of the preheated oven.</em>
        <details>
          <text> Do not allow pans to touch each other or the oven wall.
</text>
        </details>
      </step>
      <step>
        <em>Close the oven door and immediately set a timer to the specified baking time.</em>
        <details>
          <text> If there's a time range, use the median or middle number (bake it for 35 minutes for a range of 34 to 36 minutes or 53 minutes for a range of 50 to 55 minutes). Using the median will ensure that the cake won't under or over cook. Resist the urge to open the oven door during baking, as the heat will escape and may cause the cake to cook unevenly. If applicable, turn the oven light on and view through the oven window.
</text>
        </details>
      </step>
      <step>
        <em>Check for cake doneness</em>
        <details/>
      </step>
      <step>
        <em>Place the pan on a wire rack to cool for 15 to 30 minutes.</em>
        <details>
          <text> Run a butter knife around the pan edges to loosen the sides. Place the wire rack over the top of the pan, invert it, and tap it lightly to remove the cake.
</text>
        </details>
      </step>
      <step>
        <em>Let it cool completely before decorating since the heat will melt frosting and icing.</em>
        <details>
          <text> </text>
          <a href="/Frost-a-Cake" title="Frost a Cake">Frost</a>
          <text> and </text>
          <a href="/Decorate-a-Stunning-Cake" title="Decorate a Stunning Cake">decorate</a>
          <text> as desired.
</text>
        </details>
      </step>
    </method>
    <tips>
      <tip>
        <text>Double check your measurements before adding them to mixing bowls. A few tablespoons of missing or extra flour can have dramatic and undesired effects on the finished cake.</text>
      </tip>
      <tip>
        <text>If there is salt in the recipe, be very careful. A quarter of a teaspoon extra salt can make it more salty than it should be.</text>
      </tip>
      <tip>
        <text>When recipes calls for cold ingredients such as butter or cream cheese to be at room temperature, unwrap the item and leave it in a bowl on the counter for a few hours to soften. You can test the softness by poking a fork in it.</text>
      </tip>
      <tip>
        <text>Do not ice the cake before it cools. This will cause the frosting to run to the sides or slide off the cake.</text>
      </tip>
      <tip>
        <text>If you're using a different recipe, follow the directions you find in it.</text>
      </tip>
      <tip>
        <text>If you like moist cakes, substitute the oil for yogurt.</text>
      </tip>
      <tip>
        <text>Use high quality, heavy duty aluminum baking pans for even heating and best results.</text>
      </tip>
      <tip>
        <text>If you attempt to remove a hot cake from the pan, it may crack and fall apart.</text>
      </tip>
      <tip>
        <text>Always wash your hands before baking.</text>
      </tip>
    </tips>
  </document>
</root>
