<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <document>
    <categories>
      <category>
        <c>Food and Entertaining</c>
        <c>Dining Out</c>
      </category>
    </categories>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <em>Choose a lively dining spot with food you like that has quick service.</em>
        <details>
          <d>
</d>
        </details>
      </step>
      <step>
        <em>Ask for a seat at the counter or bar.</em>
        <details>
          <d> In addition to ordering a drink, the bar tender can often show you the menu. It's very common for those eating alone to sit at a counter or bar.
</d>
        </details>
      </step>
      <step>
        <em>If no bar or counter is available or you simply prefer a table, ask the hostess to seat you.</em>
        <details>
          <d> Just say "table for one please" or "it's just me this evening." Smile. It's OK, they want to serve you and are happy you came. If there is a seat by a performer, such as a piano player, ask to be seated near the entertainment.
</d>
        </details>
      </step>
      <step>
        <em>Engage the waiter if you are looking for conversation.</em>
        <details>
          <d> Ask them to recommend a dish or ask about the local weather.
</d>
        </details>
      </step>
      <step>
        <em>Bring a book, magazine, or newspaper to read while you are waiting for your meal.</em>
        <details>
          <d> This will put you at ease.
</d>
        </details>
      </step>
      <step>
        <em>Enjoy your meal.</em>
        <details>
          <d> When the waiter comes by and asks you how everything is, tell them fine and ask for the check even if you are not finished eating. This way you won't have to prolong the time you sit at the table alone.
</d>
        </details>
      </step>
      <step>
        <em>Relax, enjoy yourself and do some people watching.</em>
        <details>
          <d> If you catch someone's eye, just smile.
</d>
        </details>
      </step>
      <step>
        <em>Let the waiter know you'll be right back if you get up during your meal to use the restroom so they don't clear your plate by mistake.</em>
        <details>
          <d>
</d>
        </details>
      </step>
      <step>
        <em>Pay your bill and tip your waiter and thank the host on the way out.</em>
        <details>
          <d>
</d>
        </details>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </document>
</root>
