<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <document>
    <meta>
      <description>How to Make a Teddy Bear. It's not uncommon to give a teddy bear to a child or a loved one, but it is quite rare to give someone a teddy bear that you made yourself. If you're willing to put your sewing skills to work, you can give this...</description>
      <keywords>WikiHow, Make a Teddy Bear, wiki, how to articles, how to instructions, DIY, tips, howto, learn, how do I</keywords>
      <title>How to Make a Teddy Bear</title>
      <type>article</type>
      <url>http://www.wikihow.com/Make-a-Teddy-Bear</url>
    </meta>
    <alter_lang>
      <lang href="http://es.wikihow.com/hacer-un-osito-de-tela">es</lang>
      <lang href="http://pt.wikihow.com/Fazer-um-Ursinho-de-Pelúcia">pt</lang>
    </alter_lang>
    <categories>
      <category/>
    </categories>
    <general/>
    <methods>
      <method>
        <step>
          <em href="Sew-a-Blanket.html" title="Sew a Blanket">Sew</em>
          <details>
            <text> the arm pieces together, leaving a slit for stuffing (usually at the elbows).

</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em href="Sew-a-Winter-Coat.html" title="Sew a Winter Coat">Sew</em>
          <details>
            <text> the leg pieces together (usually along the bottom).

</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Stitch the two head profiles together from the nose to the neck.</em>
          <details/>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em href="Machine-Sew-on-a-Button.html" title="Machine Sew on a Button">Sew</em>
          <details>
            <text> the wedge shaped piece (this is known as a "gusset") between the two head pieces - from the nose or forehead to the back of the neck (this depends on the length of the gussett). You will need to line it up at the neck and pin it in place before sewing.
</text>
            <ul>
              <li>The front of the head:






</li>
              <li>The back of the head:






</li>
            </ul>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Clip all of the seams.</em>
          <details/>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Turn all of the pieces.</em>
          <details/>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Stuff the head and sew it to the top of the body, around the neck line.</em>
          <details/>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Assemble the bear by attaching the arms to the sides of the body and attaching the legs to the lower sides of the body.</em>
          <details/>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Cut, sew, turn and attach ears (if you want them, as not all bear patterns have them).</em>
          <details/>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Add facial details (like nose and mouth, etc.</em>
          <details>
            <text>) with </text>
            <a href="Choose-Embroidery-Fabric.html" title="Choose Embroidery Fabric">embroidery</a>
            <text> floss or permanent markers.

</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Sew on button eyes.</em>
          <details/>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Enjoy your new stuffed animal!</em>
          <details/>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Take good care of your teddy bear, or it may easily fall apart!</em>
          <details/>
        </step>
      </method>
    </methods>
    <tips>
      <tip>
        <ul>
          <li>Make your stitching tight so that your friend will last you a long time.</li>
          <li>Make sure when you are sewing you do the stitches quite close together.</li>
          <li>You can make teddy bear clothes as well.</li>
          <li>Embroidered eyes are better for smaller kids who tend to put every thing in their mouth.</li>
          <li>If you make clothes, get some cute material (if it's a kid girls teddy)you could get some pink material or something, and make it pajamas, sporting jerseys, jeans,tops,knit a jumper etc.</li>
        </ul>
      </tip>
    </tips>
    <warnings>
      <warning>
        <ul>
          <li>
Children should be closely supervised if they are attempting to make this.</li>
          <li>
Scissors and needles are sharp so be careful how you handle and use them.</li>
        </ul>
      </warning>
    </warnings>
    <things>
      <thing>
        <ul>
          <li>Needle and Thread
</li>
          <li>Fake Fur or other sturdy fabric
</li>
          <li>Stuffing material
</li>
          <li>Scissors
</li>
          <li>Embroidery floss or yarn
</li>
          <li>Buttons for eyes
</li>
          <li>Creativity
</li>
          <li>Patience
</li>
          <li>Hands
</li>
        </ul>
      </thing>
    </things>
    <ingredients/>
    <related_pages>
      <a href="Create-a-City-of-Teddy-Bears.html">How to Create a City of Teddy Bears</a>
      <a href="Make-a-Family-Tree-for-Your-Teddy-Bear.html">How to Make a Family Tree for Your Teddy</a>
      <a href="Make-an-Easy-Teddy-Bear.html">How to Make an Easy Teddy Bear</a>
      <a href="Make-Your-Teddy-Ready-for-a-Special-Occasion.html">How to Make Your Teddy Ready for a Special Occasion</a>
      <a href="Care-for-a-Teddy-Bear.html">How to Care for a Teddy Bear</a>
      <a href="Choose-a-Teddy-Bear.html">How to Choose a Teddy Bear</a>
      <a href="Make-Teddy-Bears-Clothes.html">How to Make Teddy Bears Clothes</a>
    </related_pages>
  </document>
</root>
