<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <document>
    <meta>
      <description>How to Start an Eraser Collection. Are you tired of collecting things that bore you like bottle caps or stickers? Collect erasers! Erasers can be super cute, making them fun to play with and come in so many shapes and sizes! Read this...</description>
      <keywords>WikiHow, Start an Eraser Collection, wiki, how to articles, how to instructions, DIY, tips, howto, learn, how do I</keywords>
      <title>How to Start an Eraser Collection</title>
      <type>article</type>
      <url>http://www.wikihow.com/Start-an-Eraser-Collection</url>
    </meta>
    <alter_lang/>
    <categories>
      <category>
        <c>Hobbies and Crafts</c>
        <c>Collecting</c>
      </category>
    </categories>
    <general>
      <title>
        <text n="h1">How to Start an Eraser Collection</text>
      </title>
      <summary>
        <text>Are you tired of collecting things that bore you like bottle caps or stickers? Collect erasers! Erasers can be super cute, making them fun to play with and come in so many shapes and sizes! Read this article on how to look after and collect erasers!</text>
      </summary>
    </general>
    <methods>
      <method>
        <step>
          <em>Find erasers.</em>
          <details>
            <text> Ask family and friends if you can have some as a small gift. If you like the Japanese erasers, you can find them in Justice, Walmart, Target, Claires, school supply stores, at book fairs - if your school has them, online stores. If you're into foohy erasers, you can find them at Walmart. Or you can do gift swaps with your friends where you give them something they like and you get what you like in return - erasers of course!
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Never use your erasers.</em>
          <details>
            <text> They become dull and out of shape! Plus they won't look cute anymore.Make sure the erasers that you buy are not used too, make sure you know that they are not used online.</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <details/>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Keep them in a divided box.</em>
          <details>
            <text> A fishing tackle/bead boxes are perfect to keep them ordered and organized. Some Japanese erasers come in cute boxes. Keep them there. The rest you should put in a divided box which you can find at dollar stores or Target.
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Show your friends and family your collection.</em>
          <details>
            <text> That way you can have something fun to do with your erasers. Do this at least once every two months.
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Play with your erasers.</em>
          <details>
            <text> If you have Japanese erasers, they are fun to take a part and put them back together again!
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Count your collection once every six months or once a year.</em>
          <details>
            <text> Always keep track of how many erasers you have.
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Find IWAKO Japanese erasers collector books on eBay or in some retail stores.</em>
          <details>
            <text> Call around to find store in your area that sell the real IWAKO erasers.
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Remember that erasers are fun, cute, and inexpensive!</em>
          <details>
            <text> That's why they're so easy to collect!
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Make sure to collect many different types and brands.</em>
          <details>
            <text n="i">Remember:</text>
            <text> there are all different types of erasers so don't just collect one brand/type of eraser.
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Consider the following:</em>
          <details>
            <text> Foohy, Crazerasers, Iwako, Gomu, Googly Erasers, Kawaii erasers, Lemon erasers, Spencil brand, etc.
</text>
            <ul>
              <li>If you are not sure what these brands are/look like, then type the brand name into Google, Bing, or another online search engine.
</li>
            </ul>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Finished.</em>
          <details/>
        </step>
      </method>
    </methods>
    <tips>
      <tip>
        <ul>
          <li>Put erasers in a box with dividers (a bead box or fishing tackle box) which are found at dollar/variety stores-- Super Cheap Auto or dollar stores.</li>
          <li>Save up for erasers. Erasers retail for about a dollar each! (not very much at all)</li>
          <li>Ask for erasers for your birthday, Christmas, and Easter.</li>
          <li>Try not to keep them in a box that will be crammed if you put your erasers in there - divided boxes will save them from melting and will keep scented erasers smelling like they should.</li>
          <li>Clean your divided box at least once a month so your erasers have a clean space in their box.</li>
        </ul>
      </tip>
    </tips>
    <warnings>
      <warning>
        <ul>
          <li>Put your erasers in an air conditioned room or in a cool spot, otherwise 'they will melt!</li>
        </ul>
      </warning>
    </warnings>
    <things>
      <thing>
        <ul>
          <li>Erasers
</li>
          <li>Money
</li>
          <li>Boxes with dividers
</li>
          <li>Internet access (if you are looking to buy erasers online)
</li>
        </ul>
      </thing>
    </things>
    <ingredients/>
    <related_pages/>
  </document>
</root>
