<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <document>
    <meta>
      <description>How to Accept Christ As Your Savior. &amp;quot;Jesus&amp;quot;... statistics show that this name is mentioned more than 3 million times an hour... Statistics even show that millions embrace Christianity each day, and that Christianity is the world's largest...</description>
      <keywords>WikiHow, Accept Christ As Your Savior, wiki, how to articles, how to instructions, DIY, tips, howto, learn, how do I</keywords>
      <title>How to Accept Christ As Your Savior</title>
      <type>article</type>
      <url>http://www.wikihow.com/Accept-Christ-As-Your-Savior</url>
    </meta>
    <alter_lang>
      <lang href="http://es.wikihow.com/aceptar-a-Jesús-como-tu-Salvador">es</lang>
    </alter_lang>
    <categories>
      <category>
        <c>Philosophy and Religion</c>
        <c>Religion</c>
        <c>Christianity</c>
      </category>
    </categories>
    <general>
      <title>
        <text n="h1">How to Accept Christ As Your Savior</text>
      </title>
      <summary>
        <text>"Jesus"... statistics show that this name is mentioned more than 3 million times an hour... Statistics even show that millions embrace Christianity each day, and that Christianity is the world's largest religion. You surely have heard of Jesus and Christianity before!</text>
      </summary>
      <summary/>
      <summary>
        <text>If you are interested in knowing more about Jesus, you are in the right place. This does not mean to rely 100% on the instructions given in this page. Asking a pastor, a Christian religious leader, a missionary, or even someone who is Christian may also be very helpful to you in order to achieve your goal in getting introduced to Jesus.</text>
      </summary>
      <summary/>
      <summary>
        <text>Before you start reading what the article has to say in detail, realize that Jesus of Nazareth fulfilled </text>
        <text n="b">all</text>
        <text> the prophecies about the </text>
        <a href="Understand-Messianic-Prophecies.html" title="Understand Messianic Prophecies">Messiah in the Jewish Bible (Old Testament)</a>
        <text>.</text>
        <text>
In the Holy Bible, John 14:9 states that Jesus said: "Whoever has seen me has seen the Father."</text>
        <text>
So, "How should you accept Christ as your Savior"?</text>
      </summary>
      <summary/>
      <summary>
        <text>This article is to show you the way through accepting Jesus as your Personal Savior.</text>
      </summary>
    </general>
    <methods>
      <method>
        <step>
          <em>Understand God's Holy Nature.</em>
          <details>
            <text> Many people do not understand the concept of the Holy Trinity, and some explain it the wrong way. Well, The Orthodox Church (the first established Christian church) (</text>
            <text n="i">This is not to promote Orthodoxy, it is just to state the first Christians' belief about the Nature of God</text>
            <text>) says: "God is one while being in a Trinity". The explanation of this is that The Father, The Son (Jesus) and The Holy Spirit are all one, the three of them refer to </text>
            <text n="b">one</text>
            <text> and only </text>
            <text n="b">one</text>
            <text> God, not by person, but by power, will and love. The Son has the same power and will as The Father and The Holy Spirit: that is why they are </text>
            <text n="b">one</text>
            <text> God, and the three of them cannot be apart in anyway, they complete each other in everything.
This does not mean if you pray to Jesus you are only praying to Him, this way, you are praying to God at once (The Father, The Son, and The Holy Spirit). The Father and the Holy Spirit sent The Son to pay the price of our sins, by acceptance of the Son, because again, God is one by will, by power and by love. So when we say that God sent Jesus to earth, we do not mean that God and Jesus are not the same, it is in the Trinity that they are different, but are one at the same time.
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Seek to understand God's plan:</em>
          <details>
            <text> "So, I need to be saved from what, and why? </text>
            <a href="Believe-in-God.html" title="Believe in God">Believing in God</a>
            <text> and The Bible is crucial to understanding "What is a savior?" and "Why be saved?" The Bible is God's revealed word to mankind, written by people so yielded to God's will that God chose them to write it. The people who wrote the books of the Bible were inspired (given the words) by God. They all agree in purpose and point to </text>
            <a href="Understand-Messianic-Prophecies.html" title="Understand Messianic Prophecies">Christ, the Messiah,</a>
            <text> though they were written over a period of more than a thousand years: The Bible teaches that all people have sin in their lives.</text>
            <text>
Sin is any act that displeases God, as sin separates us from God, who is perfect, such that the payment we are to pay for sin is </text>
            <text n="i">spiritual death</text>
            <text> -- permanent separation from God.
</text>
            <text n="blockquote">
Romans 6:23: "For the wages of sin is death, but the gift of God is eternal life in Christ Jesus our Lord."
</text>
            <text>
Spiritual Death entered into the world when Adam sinned.
</text>
            <text n="blockquote">
Genesis 2:17: "But of the tree of the knowledge of good and evil, thou shalt not eat of it: for in the day that thou eat thereof thou shalt surely die."
</text>
            <text>
&lt;blockquote Romans 5:12: </text>
            <text n="i">"Wherefore, as by one man sin entered into the world, and death by sin; and so death passed upon all men, for that all have sinned"</text>
            <text n="blockquote">
Romans 5:14: "Nevertheless death reigned from Adam to Moses, even over them that had not sinned after the similitude of Adam's transgression, who is the figure of him that was to come."
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Understand who could save you from spiritual death.</em>
          <details>
            <text> Because we are all born sinful, we are unable by our own whimsical or very deep reason--or in our own strength and morality--to please a perfect God. However, God sent His son Jesus as your representative and as your ransom from being captive.
</text>
            <text n="blockquote">
John 3:16-17 (NIV): "For God so loved the world that he gave his one and only Son, that whoever believes in him shall not perish but have eternal life. For God did not send his Son into the world to condemn the world, but to save the world through him."
</text>
            <text>
This belief is </text>
            <a href="Trust-and-Rely-on-Jesus.html" title="Trust and Rely on Jesus">trust and faith</a>
            <text> that God is who He says He is. He provided the payment for our sin by His own son’s taking our place as a substitute. All sins, past, present and future were forgiven by Christ at the cross, although men condemned Him who knew no sin to a cruel, physical death.
</text>
            <text n="blockquote">
Hebrews 10:10: "And by that will, we have been made holy through the sacrifice of the body of Jesus Christ once for all."
</text>
            <text n="blockquote">
Someone had to pay with his life for all of our sins. Hebrews 9:22 (NIV)"In fact, the law requires that... without the shedding of blood there is no forgiveness."
</text>
            <text>
Jesus died to pay for the sins of man. However, he rose again, conquering death and making it possible to be saved; so we accept Jesus when the Holy Spirit calls you--not merely our thinking and reasoning it out, but realizing that it is based on God's provision and His gift. In fact, Christianity is not just a volunteer religion. (Jesus called his disciples, they generally didn't come to him already determined to follow him.) In the same way we cannot merely "accept" Jesus, but we can receive what he gives us through the </text>
            <a href="Receive-the-Holy-Spirit-as-per-The-Bible-3.html" title="Receive the Holy Spirit as per The Bible">Holy Spirit</a>
            <text>. The Holy Spirit does call us--all to repentance and to follow God--through the preaching of God's Word and accepting the Good News (Gospel). Those who do not believe have rejected God's free gift, those who do believe only have faith because it is the free gift of God (grace).
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Admit that you have sinned.</em>
          <details>
            <text> It is a prerequisite to accepting Christ. Once you understand that we are and you are a sinner and that all have sinned, turn to the Lord Jesus Christ for forgiveness by </text>
            <a href="Repent-According-to-the-Bible.html" title="Repent According to the Bible">repenting</a>
            <text> of your sins.
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Profess Jesus as your savior.</em>
          <details>
            <text> Romans 10:13, "For whosoever shall call upon the name of the Lord shall be saved." Say, "Father in Heaven, I believe that Jesus died for my sins." And God will impart eternal life to your spirit.</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Understand that Jesus said to receive or accept Him we must receive whom He sent.</em>
          <details>
            <text n="sup">[1]</text>
            <text>(John13:20) That is the Holy Spirit </text>
            <text n="sup">[2]</text>
            <text> (John15:26)</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Remember to ask for the Holy Spirit.</em>
          <details>
            <text> The Holy Spirit does not come automatically when a person believes but Jesus says everyone who asks receives (Luke11:9-13)
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Taste and see that the gifts of the Lord are good.</em>
          <details>
            <text> Believe that God loves you; He has shown this by giving His Son to face your punishment and die in your place as your sacrifice for all you've done wrong and for all your sins.
</text>
            <ul>
              <li>
Repentance is the decision to turn away from sin and to turn to God and obey him. Once you have done this, every other step will fall into place. If you still have a hard time with this concept, trust Jesus as Lord over you as well as Savior.</li>
            </ul>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Talk to God in your own words.</em>
          <details>
            <text> There is no protocol to follow in order to talk to God. God listens to your prayers even if you do not say them. But this does not mean He does not like to hear you seek His help and His forgiveness. God does not judge you violently, because He just is not a human being like us! He is your Father; He is your Brother and your personal Protector/and Mediator, and He wants to become you Best Friend! God wants you to confess your sins to Him, because He wants to forgive you, and He wants you to tell Him your secrets, even though He knows everything about you. This is a promise:
Matthew 7:7-9 "7 Ask and it will be given to you [worshippers]; seek and you will find; knock and the door will be opened to you. 8 For everyone who asks receives; he who seeks finds; and to him who knocks, the door will be opened. 9 [For] Which of you, if his son asks for bread, will give him a stone?"
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Tell God what you want to say to Him.</em>
          <details>
            <text> But realize that: John 9:31 "Now [in this] we know that God [listens] hears </text>
            <text n="b">not</text>
            <text> sinners: but if any man be a worshipper of God, and does His will [receives Christ], him He hears [answers]." Talking to God can be in many forms, whether in a prayer or in an ordinary way as in talking to others. Here's a prayer suggestion, </text>
            <text n="i">please read this suggestion and use your own words. Without reading such words, just tell God what you want to say to Him in your own words, expressing all your love to Him</text>
            <text>:</text>
            <text n="i">"My God and my Savior, I know I have sinned before you, and I know about all the bad things I have in my life. But with you my God, I shall never fear even the worst things in life, because you have sent your only and true Son, Jesus, to be crucified, and to pay the price of my own sins. I come to you my God to confess everything I have done in my life, and to tell you I am sorry. I am here to declare you King on my life, my thoughts and my actions. I want you to be my Savior. Please God, forgive me, for I have sinned before you. My God and my LORD, reign over my life, because your reign is perfect and your kingdom will never see an end. Amen"</text>
            <text>
Feel the presence of God in faith while kneeling. Kneeling is efficient, if you want to concentrate on nothing but your prayer.
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
        <step>
          <em>Be baptized in accordance with the New Testament.</em>
          <details>
            <a href="Tell-Someone-That-Water-Baptism-Is-Important-for-Christianity.html" title="Tell Someone That Water Baptism Is Important for Christianity">Baptism</a>
            <text> is used to signify the death and burial of our sinful person and our resurrection as a forgiven Christian through the power of the </text>
            <a href="Receive-the-Holy-Spirit-as-per-The-Bible-3.html" title="Receive the Holy Spirit as per The Bible">Holy Spirit</a>
            <text> just as Jesus was (Romans8:11, Col. 2:12,13). Baptism is commanded "for the forgiveness of your sins" (Acts 2:38) Prayer and faith was not enough to save the devout Cornelius in Acts 10. He was commanded to be baptized. (v. 48) After every example of a person having faith and believing in Christ, he or she is always baptized to complete his or her salvation! (Acts 2:41; 8:13; 8:37,38; 9:18; 16:30-33, etc)
</text>
          </details>
        </step>
      </method>
      <method/>
    </methods>
    <tips>
      <tip>
        <ul>
          <li>Now that you have chosen to accept Christ and receive his forgiveness for your sin, don't take advantage of his forgiveness and commit wrong like watching bad movies, reading porn magazines, etc. Don't beat yourself up if you do sin, remember that we will only be perfect once we get to heaven! Doing bad things and saying that God will forgive you is not what it means to accept Christ.</li>
          <li>Remember that God is the Saviour of all mankind, not just your kind, or those that have been taught in the ways of a religion. Anyone who accepts Christ as Savior and follows Him in the new life, as God would have one live it, will be accepted into heaven joyfully. For ours is a forgiving God, who gave his son for us, to forgive all original sin, and therefore, these children are no less accessible to heaven than the Pope or Mother Teresa.</li>
          <li>Consider whether the whole family of God (including His church) is your family: recall this scene at the cross, "Jesus therefore, seeing his mother, and the disciple [John] standing by, whom he loved, says to his mother, 'Woman, behold thy son'. Then He says unto the disciple, 'Behold thy mother'. And from that hour the disciple took her to his own home." (John 19:26) You can receive Christ and make welcome His whole family to your heart and home. (Catholics traditionally ask Christ's Blessed Mother to be their Blessed Mother too.)</li>
          <li>If you have accepted Christ as your savior,

Romans 10:13 (KJV)
"For whosoever shall call upon the name of the Lord shall be saved"

You are now a child of God. Just believe what the bible says, and accept what it says practically, as if what it says is exactly what it means.</li>
          <li>Plug into a church or a youth group. They will help you know more about God and be closer to him. Don't be too proud by thinking that you can walk with God alone. Christian friends build you up and encourage you, so plug into a church as soon as possible.</li>
          <li>You can approach God anytime. Talk to him as you would with a regular friend. We have direct access to him!</li>
          <li>If you want an alternative viewpoint on accepting Christ, see Overcome Christophobia.</li>
          <li>Christianity may be metaphorically compared to a race. A race to reach the finish line (Heaven) is our ultimate goal, but how we run the race is more important than when we finish the race. We pause to help others along the way (benevolence, and bringing others to Christ), and sometimes stumble on obstacles in the way (our sin, others' sin). Christianity isn't an easy path. It may be easy to 'run the first lap', but the race becomes more difficult as we mature in our faith. Never forget to ask Jesus' help, because we are not alone in the 'race'.</li>
          <li>Church does not mean a building. It means, and has from the beginning, a group of people who have accepted Jesus as the One True God meeting in the same place to celebrate what they have and learn from each other how God is working in their lives. This can happen anywhere, at set times, or even spontaneously.</li>
          <li>If your parents don't approve of the church thing, seek the help of the pastor or youth leader of the church you want to go to, or any other church. Technically, you aren't a member of the church yet; you're just seeking the help of a pastor or youth leader.</li>
          <li>A prophet named Isaiah goes into great detail, proofs, scriptures for you to understand. Read the whole chapter of Isaiah 53, but here are verses 3—5, "He was despised and rejected by men...:
Surely he took up our infirmities and carried our sorrows,
yet we considered him stricken by God, smitten by him, and afflicted.
But he was pierced for our transgressions,
he was crushed for our iniquities;
the punishment that brought us peace was upon him, and
by his wounds we are healed." Yes, Jesus fulfilled those longstanding prophecies concerning the Messiah, completely.[3]
</li>
          <li>Read examples of others who have fully accepted Jesus and his teachings for your encouragement [4]
</li>
        </ul>
      </tip>
    </tips>
    <warnings>
      <warning>
        <ul>
          <li>For some people becoming a Christian is an emotional step; for others it is a simple act of trust -- receiving Him without emotions. God will save you with or without emotions.</li>
          <li>Avoid having a closed mind: but keep an open core willingness to accept faith as totally relevant and an open mind to the Biblical account and Bible-doctrines are needed. "You are the light of the World." -- but, a candle cannot be lit, if it has no wick (to be lighted), like a core/wick of faith in God, to spread the light of Jesus Christ in the shadows of non-belief.</li>
          <li>Do not expect that this is an easy life. Some example may be found in books like Jesus Freaks, The Hiding Place, Boom, Heavenly Man, or Christian magazines such as OpenDoors International or Voice of the Martyrs to find out what true faith looks like worldwide. People may make fun of you for doing this. But that doesn't mean that you'll be happy or unhappy for the rest of your life. You can have eternal joy for the rest of your life, knowing that you've accepted God and that you are accepted, in turn, as His friend, brother/sister.</li>
          <li>Don't ever suppose that God doesn't care about what you do from now on. Always be aware that he doesn't want you to go back and do the sin that you may be used to. He has made you a different person for good so that you can live 'above' sin, not fall back into it. Always remember that you will undoubtedly be tempted to sin, but you can pray daily that God will keep you from failing. If you do sin, ask forgiveness from God right away, and ask him to help you not to do it again.</li>
          <li>The grace of Jesus covers all sins. None of your words or actions can ever keep you from salvation and God's loving embrace. The only exception to this is blasphemy of the Holy Spirit, but this only applies to those who are already believers and speak vile words or commit vile acts against the Holy Spirit.

Luke 12:10 (NIV)
"And everyone who speaks a word against the Son of Man will be forgiven, but anyone who blasphemes against the Holy Spirit will not be forgiven."

Aside from this only exception, the grace of Jesus is yours when you believe in Him -- when you commit yourself to Christ.

Ephesians 1:12-14 (NIV)
"And you also were included in Christ when you heard the word of truth, the gospel of your salvation. Having believed, you were marked in him with a seal, the promised Holy Spirit, who is a deposit guaranteeing our inheritance until the redemption of those who are God's possession—to the praise of his glory."

</li>
          <li>God will always love you for no matter what you do. And he always has loved you. But now that you've become a Christian, you must not do some things that you have previously done. Just because you're a new person, doesn't mean you can do other things you've done before that were wrong.</li>
          <li>Be aware, once you've accepted Christ into your life, that persecution knows no bounds. Now that you understand and feel the love of Jesus, you may become one of Satan's prime targets. Fret not, though, because nothing on earth or in Hell can harm your faith with God daily at your side. Do not worry about it, but rather remember this when you face temptations to sin.</li>
          <li>If you have wronged someone else, go and apologize without cuts or put-downs. No matter how hard it may be, it will always be worth it to make restitution. Then, do not dwell on it, but get back to following Jesus and His example.</li>
          <li>Do not expect all your family and friends to like the new you, but it is OK, Jesus never said that it would be easy, He just said that it would be the truth. This does not mean at all that your family members will not accept Jesus. They just need to have the power of God in them and work in them so that they might become new like you.</li>
          <li>For more advice, talk to a pastor at a church, or another Christian, or just talk to God. The Holy Spirit will guide you all the days of your life, and He knows what's best for you, and always remember, God loves you.


Learn recommended Bible scriptures (about your salvation and Life in Christ) that you may wish to commit to long-term memory: here is a free resource to aid in memorizing for retention. Your long term memory is formed of memory traces from a mix of spaced repetitions, discussions and reviews, experience, associations, images and appreciation of the importance of the information, and renewed rehearsals will establish longer lasting connections with less effort than the original learning.[5]


</li>
          <li>
Learn recommended Bible scriptures (about your salvation and Life in Christ) that you may wish to commit to long-term memory: here is a free resource to aid in memorizing for retention. Your long term memory is formed of memory traces from a mix of spaced repetitions, discussions and reviews, experience, associations, images and appreciation of the importance of the information, and renewed rehearsals will establish longer lasting connections with less effort than the original learning.[5]
</li>
        </ul>
      </warning>
    </warnings>
    <things>
      <thing>
        <ul>
          <li>The Bible: In some countries there are few Bibles, and there is persecution of Christians -- or lack of funds and supply. The word of God, especially the Book of John in the Bible, tells how to be a Christian. Owning a Bible isn't -- but access to the Bible is -- essential (ie: written or verbal communications; see below in Sources and Citations for Internet, online Bibles).
</li>
          <li>Other Christians to encourage and guide you. If you don't know any, praise God for the mission field that He has placed you in! You may feel inexperienced, but read the Bible and ask God what He wants. Do those things, but verify that it is truly Him by comparing the plan with His word (the Bible).
</li>
        </ul>
      </thing>
    </things>
    <ingredients/>
    <related_pages>
      <a href="Confront-Sin-Being-Done-by-Believers-of-Christ.html">How to Confront Sin Being Done by Believers of Christ</a>
      <a href="Accept-Jesus-Into-Your-Life.html">How to Accept Jesus Into Your LIfe</a>
      <a href="Overcome-Christophobia.html">How to Overcome Christophobia</a>
      <a href="Understand-Messianic-Prophecies.html">How to Understand Prophecies About the Messiah</a>
      <a href="Be-Born-Again.html">How to Be Born Again</a>
      <a href="Pray-Effectively-(Christianity).html">How to Pray Effectively (Christianity)</a>
      <a href="Receive-the-Holy-Spirit-as-per-The-Bible-3.html">How to Receive the Holy Spirit as per The Bible</a>
      <a href="Have-a-Personal-Relationship-With-God-(Christianity).html">How to Have a Personal Relationship With God (Christianity)</a>
      <a href="Read-the-Bible.html">How to Read the Bible</a>
      <a href="Be-a-Christian.html">How to Become A Christian</a>
    </related_pages>
  </document>
</root>
